This is where I begin, isn't it?
To make my wish come true.
I, Kobato... am ready!
Kobato.
What should I do?
Even the most obvious of things
Are always such a challenge
I want to laugh when I'm happy
And sing whenever I want
Is all
They say my dreams will come true someday
But when will "someday" come?
I can't wait forever
On "1, 2, 3!" I'll spread open my arms
And let the light gather around me
Where is it?
Please tell me what I can do
I make the most of getting hurt
And run with all my might
Despite how many dozens of times I fall
And start crying
I surprise myself
In how much I believe in tomorrow
...A Girl's Wish.
Kobato...
Yes, Ioryogi-san.
We have finally arrived.
This is the Ningenkai, where people live.
You do understand that?
Yes, I do.
And for your wish to come true, well that all
depends on how hard you try here in Ningenkai.
You understand that, too.
Yes, of course!
Well, if you understand
Then why are we stuffed in this hole
immediately upon our arrival?!
But... but I thought it would be
fun if we could hide out,
kinda like a secret meeting or something...
We didn't come here so you could have fun!
Kobato Hanato!
Yes sir!
What is your wish?
There's a place I want to go!
And what did he tell you you need
to do before you could do that?!
I must collect a "bottle full of broken hearts"!
Before that?!
I need you to give me the "bottle"!
To get that "bottle"?!
I need to pass a test to see if
I'm worthy of living here!
Exactly!
I am going to spend the day today,
checking to see if you have enough
common sense to live in the Ningenkai!
The test has already begun!
Under the supervision and verdict of yours truly!
Do you hear me young lady?!
Y-Yes sir I understand... sir.
Your test will be judged on how
well you can behave "here".
Now go, Kobato!
Go and do the right things,
in this park where spring has come!
What are you waiting for?!
Yes sir!
So, what do you think, Ioryogi-san?
Are you a basket worm hibernating until spring?!
Give me a break...
Are you saying you can't even
act naturally in a park?
I'm sorry.
You're impossible.
Why couldn't you at least take the trash out?
I'm going to miss my bus!
Excuse me!
No, not at all.
Oh no! I'm going to be late for work!
Ioryogi-san.
Looks like she dropped it.
Perfect. Here's the next test.
Huh?
Let's see what you're going
to do now with that trash.
Y-Yes sir.
Garbage disposal...
Where's the garbage disposal?
I found it!
Here...
Here?
I'll put this...
You'll put this?
Please cooperate in reducing garbage.
The crows...
They're probably after the garbage.
They'll start picking at you if you don't hurry.
They're after...
The crows...
They want the garbage...
Here you are, crows!
What are you doing!?
That surprised me.
What was the big idea, calling the crows over?!
But the crows, they seemed to be hungry.
And it said right on the sign, to reduce trash.
I'm no longer calling you Kobato!
"Dobato" is a good enough name for you!
That's not nice.
Hey, sweetie.
Are you here alone?
Wanna go for coffee?
Coffee?
There's a cool place down the street.
Yeah, right. Picking up girls in mid-afternoon?
We'll pay.
You're buying?!
Thank you very much!
Cool, shall we go then?
Okay!
Aren't we lucky, Ioryogi-san?
Are you out of your mind?!
What the heck did you come here to do?!
What? But they're going to treat us...
Are you okay?!
Are you hurt?
Hey! What did you just do to us?!
Huh?
Hey! Who do you think
you're messing with?!
You guys get on my nerves.
Oh man, she was with a guy!
U-Um...
Thank y-
Don't flatter yourself just because
some guy was kind to you.
Thank y-
Don't flatter yourself just because
some guy was kind to you.
What?!
I wasn't flattering myself!
Well, you looked pretty happy.
Anyone would misunderstand.
I'm so glad it's such a nice day!
A lot of customers here to view the flowers.
It's going to get busy!
Isn't it, Fujimoto?
Yes it is.
Oh, can you take these out?
Sure.
That cat was really cute.
Here you are.
Let me take these away for you.
Oh, thanks.
He's cool!
I hear you. You wanna ask him his name?
What?
You could show them a little service.
At least smile or something.
The girls would be all over you.
I'm not interested in having girls come after me.
What a dude.
I'm sorry. I forgot to turn it off.
Yomogi Kindergarten
Hello, Fujimoto speaking.
What's the matter, Ms. Sayaka?
They showed up at the kindergarten again?!
Hang on, I'll be there as soon as I can!
Sir, something has come up!
I've got to get somewhere right away.
I wonder what's going on.
Look at all the people over there, Ioryogi-san.
Could be a flower viewing festival.
Whatever it is, something sure smells good!
Let's go take a look.
Yes. Let's do that.
Wow!
They're in full bloom.
They're so beautiful!
Miss, can you get the ball?
Uh, sure!
Okay!
Thank you very much!
Here I go.
There!
Woah! Wh-What was that?!
I'm sorry!
Guess it couldn't be helped...
Really, I am so sorry!
I'm short staffed as it is...
Please let me help you!
Huh?
Let me make it up to you by helping, please!
What?
Can I get another beer, please?
Roger!
My waiter suddenly had to go home, you see.
You're such a great help, thank you.
Really?
I am so happy to be of help to you!
To be of help is a rarity for Kobato.
Excuse me. Is our hot pot ready yet?
Yes sir, right away!
Please take this over to them.
Are you listening to me?
Sure I'm listening.
Here you are!
Oh thanks. Could you stew it for us?
Huh?
Thank you!
So you see...
Yes, you were saying?
You want me to stew it in the hot pot?
This will be a good thing to test.
Let's take a look at how well le chef
Kobato handles the hot pot!
There!
Wh-What the? The water's not even boiling.
Don't put anything in yet.
Oh no, not the meat! No, not yet!
Now why on earth would you add milk?!
Why not? It's healthy!
Woah, hold the chocolate bar!
Eating sweets gives you energy!
No! Not natto!
Yikes!
Looks like a painting of hell...
B-But it would be a waste not to... hm?
Huh?
Delicious!
You know, it is!
Give it a try, you'd be surprised!
Huh?
This is good.
It really is.
Great!
Delicious!
Young lady, I'm going to put
this on my regular menu.
Thank you so much!
You're pretty good for a young lady.
Now you've made me want to try some.
You're just a Dobato, and a cheeky one at that.
Kobato, as far as hot pot knowledge
is concerned, you get a zero.
What?!
But in the end you concocted something that
actually tasted good, so I'll give you forty.
Is that all?
Here you go, honey. How do you like that?
What's the matter?
She won't stop crying.
Aw, I'm sorry!
Oh dear, it's not your fault.
Don't let it worry you.
But...
This child is always like this at night.
I often bring her here to the park so that
she doesn't keep the neighbors awake.
She just won't go to sleep until
she tires herself out crying.
Oh, is that right?
Her mother used to be by her side all the time
and sang to her when she started up like this.
Then she'd settle down.
Where is her mother now?
Right now, she's out working hard for the baby.
That's why I have to take good care of her.
But an old lady's singing doesn't
help to settle her down.
Let me sing to her!
What?
Let me sing for the baby!
Though I probably can't sing like her mother.
Could you, then?
Yes!
I'll try to sing my very best.
Flowers blossom in the spring
Skies in the summer reach far and wide
Every time I think of this
I'm all right. I just got back to work.
Precious thoughts spread across in my heart
Please don't worry about a thing, Ms. Sayaka.
In the morning when it rains
Uh, no, there's this song...
On those days when the windows stay closed
My heart shimmers with the light
Light shining brightly above the clouds
The voices are calling to me
From way over yonder, from far I can hear
Voices of laughter
Voices of singing
Echoing voices of the wind
In happiness and in sadness
Well, I'll have to give her credit for singing.
She does it very well.
In happiness and in sadness
In all I behold and all that I live for
I guess that goes for Kohaku, too.
With my hand in your hand
Your hand in my hand
Together, we are one and whole
Um... Um, I...
That was quite nice.
The baby seems to have stopped crying.
I'm so glad.
Thanks to you, dear.
Hey sing us another one!
We want to hear more!
Yeah, more! Please!
What? What?! What?!!
There's a stage over there! Come on let's go!
We got all these gifts from those people.
Well they said it was for your singing.
May as well keep it.
Um... so, so! How did I do on the test?
Huh? Oh, the test...
Kobato Hanato!
Y-Y-Y-Yes sir!
In the first half, you were totally wild and
unpredictable and in the second half,
well that hot pot was a product of luck.
But your singing was okay...
Uh, then...
You fail!
But you said my singing was okay!
The first half was just too much of a mess!
Aw, come on!
You're mean. You're just too mean!
I really tried, you know!
Well, you almost made it. Too bad!
Oh please!
Dear?
Oh you're the grandmother
from earlier this evening.
Good evening.
Good evening, young lady
with the beautiful voice.
I'm so happy to see you again.
Thank you so much for earlier.
I just wanted to offer you a word of thanks.
That was the first time the baby enjoyed
someone other than her mother singing for her.
She was having such a great time and the
next moment, she'd fallen asleep.
I wanted to stay and thank you for what you
did for her, but I had to take her home.
Sorry for leaving without a word.
Oh no, there's no need to be sorry.
Your singing was truly wonderful.
Please let me hear you again sometime.
Wh-Why sure.
Good night, then.
Oh, yes, good night.
Hm?
Kobato Hanato!
Yes sir!
You pass.
Huh?
Why, this is...
...the bottle, isn't it?
Yep.
It is the real thing, isn't it?
Yes it is.
That grandmother's gratitude to you
brings you up to a score of 100.
You have passed the test.
Is it really, really, really... the real thing?
If you don't want it, give it back!
No, no! I want it, I want it!
So if I heal broken hearts and collect the
pieces in this bottle until it's full...
Your wish will come true.
But you've only just gotten the bottle.
Yes.
Kobato Hanato! What is your wish?!
There's a place I want to go.
Before you can do that, what do you need?
I must fill this bottle with broken hearts.
Okay. Now. It's show time. This is only the
beginning. There's a long way to go!
Yes sir! I'm ready!
Get that smirk off of your face. You'd better
know what you're up against, Dobato!
Aw, that's not nice!
Dobato
My name is Kobato! Kobato Hanato!
Dobato's good enough for you!
If you don't like that, it's Dabada!
Dabada
What?! Dabada?!
Everyone dreams of flying
But they let gravity trick them
Honestly, everyone is already able to fly
I bet the reason that child looks so terribly sad
Is because he
Accidentally lost his shadow somewhere
In that case
If I could just tell you, "Thank you,"
And you laugh and reply, "Thank you"
That exchange would fill you with joy
It would make you feel so happy
There's nothing to worry about
Since we're together
It's strange how I'm crying
Even though I'm happy
Next episode
...The Shining Kompeito.
Even though I'm happy
Next episode
...The Shining Kompeito.